Person A lights a candle
甲点燃一支蜡烛
Its light spreads in all directions
蜡烛的亮光朝各个方向传播
forming a bubble that grows
形成了一个膨胀的泡泡
Person B only sees the candle light up when he receives the light
乙只有在光线到达后才能看见蜡烛的亮光
or in other words when he enters the bubble
也就是他进入这个泡泡的时候
Once he has seen the candle light up
一旦他看见蜡烛点亮
B cannot get out of the bubble
他就没法离开这个泡泡了
because to do so he would have to exceed the speed of light
除非他比光速更快
the surface of a star emits bubbles of light as time goes by
随着时间流逝，恒星的表面释放出一个个泡泡
but if the star collapses in on itself
但如果恒星自身发生坍缩
it can become so compact
它就可能变得十分密实
that its gravity pulls the fabric of space at the speed of light
以至于自身的引力以光速使空间收缩
at some point
在某个时刻
its surface emits a final bubble
它的的表面释放出最后一个泡泡
which attempts to grow
这个泡泡试图扩张
but space contracts the other way
但空间是向里收缩的
such that it remains static
这样一来，泡泡就会维持静止
once inside it's impossible to get out
一旦进入其中，就不可能再出来了
it is a black hole
这就是黑洞
black holes are bubbles of light frozen by gravity
黑洞是被引力困住的光线泡泡
[Music]